topcoder.com 2016-04-06

# Privacy Policy – topcoder

This privacy statement covers the Web site www.topcoder.com (“Site”) owned and operated by Appirio Inc. (“TopCoder”, “Appirio”). This privacy statement describes how Appirio Inc. collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web site. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [www.topcoder.com](https://www.topcoder.com/). If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact security@appirio.com. In order to view relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe Seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

Appirio Inc. participates in the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce. As part of our participation in the safe harbor, we have agreed to TRUSTe dispute resolution for disputes relating to our compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Framework. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor you should first contact us (as provided above). If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by Internet at http://www.truste.com/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php, fax at 415-520-3420, or mail to TRUSTe Safe Harbor Compliance Dept., click for mailing address. 

If you are faxing or mailing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information: the name of company, the alleged privacy violation, your contact information, and whether you would like the particulars of your complaint shared with the company. For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe’s dispute resolution process, click here or request this information from TRUSTe at any of the addresses listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process shall be conducted in English. For human resources data we have agreed to cooperate with Data Protection Authorities. 

Any questions, comments or complaints about the data practices (including without limitation compliance with data privacy principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, access, security, data integrity, or enforcement) of a hosted online OnBoarding software customer or partner for whom Appirio processes data should be addressed to that customer or partner. 

Appirio Inc. complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Appirio Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Appirio Inc’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

### Privacy Policy Updates

Due to the Internet’s rapidly evolving nature, TopCoder may need to make material changes to this policy or update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If so, TopCoder will post its updated Privacy Policy on our homepage with a prominent material change notice prior to the change becoming effective. If any modification is unacceptable to you, you shall cease using this Site. If you do not cease using this Site, you will be deemed to have accepted the change. 

### Information Collection, Use, Choices and Data Integrity

You can generally visit our Site without revealing any personally identifiable information about yourself. However, in certain sections of this Site, we may invite you to contact us with questions or comments, register for webinars or events, participate in contests and surveys, or request information or more information about our Services. Due to the nature of some of these activities, we may collect personally identifiable information, such as your name, address, email address, account information, wire information and phone number, username, password and any other personally identifiable information you elect to include in your communications sent to us. In certain circumstances, we also may ask for your title, company name and additional company information such as annual revenues. We may also ask for demographic information in order to provide you with a more personalized experience. If you request more information about our Services or participate in a contest, we may use your personally identifiable information to send you the information you have requested or information about the contest. We may use your personally identifiable information to register you to use our Site, deliver certain goods, services or information you have requested, provide you with notices regarding Services you have purchased or products and services of our partners you may want to purchase in the future and other TopCoder news, verify your authority to enter the Site and improve the content and general administration of the Site. You have the choice to opt-out of receiving emails from us about our Services or products and services of our partners, including promotions and events and other news. You can opt out of being contacted by us regarding our Services or products and services of our partners, including promotions and events as well as other news at any time by sending an email to remove@appirio.com. We may receive a confirmation when you open an e-mail from TopCoder if your computer supports this type of program, in order to help us make e-mails more interesting and helpful. In performing and providing our Services to you, we may have access to personally identifiable information that is included in the data that you provide to us so that we can provide our Services for you. For example, we may have access to certain usernames that you use to login to third party services and websites and data that you store in your accounts with such third party services. We do not store or use such personally identifiable information other than as necessary to perform our Services and provide our Services to you. We use your personally identifiable information for the purposes for which it was collected as set forth above and not for promotional purposes or for use by third parties for promotional purposes. 

### Cookies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Appirio and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers like Bizo, Google, KISSmetrics and Marketo. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference), and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited. 

### Log Files

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you. 

### LSOs

We use HTML 5 local storage objects (LSOs) to store content information and preferences [or – other uses]. Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use LSOs to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. 

### Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). (Or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)) Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. We use Google AdSense to publish ads on this site. When you view or click on an ad a cookie will be set to help better provide advertisements that may be of interest to you on this and other Web sites. You may opt-out of the use of this cookie by visiting Google’s Advertising and Privacy page: <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>

### Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

### Single Sign-On

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form.  Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network. 

### Testimonials

We post testimonials on our web site which contain personally identifiable information such as the customer’s name. We do obtain the customer’s consent prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you want to remove your personally identifiable information that is being displayed on our website under public pages please send your request to security@appirio.com. 

### Blogs, Forums and Chatrooms

If you use a bulletin board, blog, or chat room on this Site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at support@topcoder.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

### Aggregate Information

The Site may track the total number of visitors to our Site, IP addresses, the number of visitors to each page of our Site and items clicked on our Site. Additionally, when we provide our Services to you, we may track aggregate and anonymous data that you provide to use to provide our Services to benchmark and improve our Services and ensure you are complying with the terms of your license from us. We may use this data in the aggregate, but such information will be maintained, used and disclosed in aggregate form only and it will not contain personally identifiable information. We may use such aggregate information to diagnose server problems, analyze trends, administer and improve the Site, track users’ movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. 

### Onward Transfer

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may provide or provide access to your personally identifiable information and the data generated by cookies and the aggregate information to the vendors and service agencies that we may engage to assist us. For example, a consultant may have access to your personally identifiable information while the consultant is performing services on our behalf if the services require access to your systems. Such third parties are required to agree to a confidentiality agreement with us regarding your personally identifiable information and we only authorize them to use your personally identifiable information that they may have access to as necessary to perform services on our behalf and not for their own marketing purposes. We also may provide your personally identifiable information to our third party business service partners and they may use your personally identifiable information to send you marketing and promotional information. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us at support@topcoder.com. As part of our provision of Services to you, you may request us to publish your data which may contain personally identifiable information on third party websites. Other people will be able to view such data if such data is published on third party websites. We will also disclose your personally identifiable information and the aggregate information if we reasonably believe we are required to do so by law, court order, warrant, subpoena, legal process or regulation or in cooperation with any governmental investigation. We may transfer your personally identifiable information and the aggregate information to a successor entity upon a merger, consolidation or other corporate reorganization in which Appirio participates or to a purchaser of all or substantially all of Appirio’s assets to which this Site relates. 

### Children’s Privacy

TopCoder recognizes the privacy interests of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. Neither our Site nor our services are intended for children under the age of 13. TopCoder does not target its services or this Site to children under 13. TopCoder does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If it is discovered that we have collected PII from someone under 13 we will delete that information immediately. 

### Access

You may correct, amend or delete your personally identifiable information that TopCoder stores, except where the burden or expense to TopCoder of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to your privacy or where the legitimate rights of persons other than you would be violated. Please email security@appirio.com to correct, amend or delete your personally identifiable information. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

### Links to Third Party Sites

The Site may provide links to other Web sites or resources over which TopCoder does not have control (“External Web Sites”). Such links do not constitute an endorsement by TopCoder of those External Web Sites. You acknowledge that the Site is providing these links to you only as a convenience, and further agree that neither TopCoder nor Appirio is not responsible for the content of such External Web Sites. Your use of External Web Sites and any products purchased on such External Web Sites is subject to the terms of use and privacy policies located on the linked to External Web Sites. 

### Security

We may employ procedural and technological security measures that are reasonably designed to help protect your personally identifiable information from loss, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. The Site may use encryption, password protection and other security measures to help prevent unauthorized access to your personally identifiable information. 

### Questions

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy please contact us via email at security@appirio.com or at:

760 Market Street, 11th Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94102  
Tel: (415) 663-4433  
Toll Free: (888) 680-SaaS (7227)Lo

_Effective Date December 10, 2015_
